the instruction was to simply pay attention to my breath,
得到的指示就是， 简单地注意自己的呼吸，
and when my mind wandered, to bring it back.
而当我的心思开始游走了， 就把它拉回来。
Sounded simple enough.
听起来很简单。
Yet I'd sit on these silent retreats,
但当我在静坐冥想时，
sweating through T-shirts in the middle of winter.
即使在冬天也会让我汗流浃背。
I'd take naps every chance I got because it was really hard work.
我抓到机会就会小睡片刻， 因为真的很辛苦。
Actually, it was exhausting.
实际上，是精疲力竭了。
The instruction was simple enough
指示是很简单，
but I was missing something really important.
但我错过了很多重要之地方。
So why is it so hard to pay attention?
那为什么专注会这么困难呢？
Well, studies show
根据研究指出，
that even when we're really trying to pay attention to something --
就算是我们尝试着专注于一些事情 --
like maybe this talk --
就好像这个演讲 --
at some point,
到某个时间点，
about half of us will drift off into a daydream,
我们当中会有一半的人， 都会恍惚进入神游状态，
or have this urge to check our Twitter feed.
或是会有一股冲动， 想去查看一下推特的内容。
So what's going on here?
这到底是怎么回事呢？
It turns out that we're fighting one of the most evolutionarily-conserved
原来我们与之抗争的， 是一种最近被科学界发现的 --
one that's conserved
它会被保存在
back to the most basic nervous systems known to man.
人类所知的最基本神经系统里面。
This reward-based learning process
这类奖励为本的学习过程，
is called positive and negative reinforcement,
称之为正强化和负强化，
and basically goes like this.
基本上是这样运行的。
We see some food that looks good,
我们看到了看起来好吃的食物，
our brain says, "Calories! ... Survival!"
我们的大脑会说：「卡路里！...生存！」
We eat the food, we taste it --
然后我们把食物吃下去， 我们尝了味道--
it tastes good.
嘗起來不錯。
And especially with sugar,
尤其是有加糖的，
our bodies send a signal to our brain that says,
我们的身体就会向大脑发出讯息说，
"Remember what you're eating and where you found it."
「要记住你吃的是什么和在哪里找到的。」
We lay down this context-dependent memory
我们种下了这「情境关连」的记忆，
and learn to repeat the process next time.
且学懂了下次再重覆这个过程。
See food,
看到食物、
eat food, feel good,
吃下食物、感觉很好。
repeat.
重覆。
Trigger, behavior, reward.
触发、行为、奖励。
Simple, right?
很简单，对不对？
Well, after a while, our creative brains say,
然后过一阵子后， 我们富有创意的脑袋就会说：
"You know what?
「 你知道吗？
You can use this for more than just remembering where food is.
你不只可以利用这个过程 来记住食物在哪里，
You know, next time you feel bad,
而且还可以在下一次你感觉糟糕时，
why don't you try eating something good so you'll feel better?"
尝试吃一些好吃的食物， 来让你感觉好一点？ 」
We thank our brains for the great idea,
我们要感谢自己的脑袋里 有这么好的点子，
try this and quickly learn
试着做且学得快，
that if we eat chocolate or ice cream when we're mad or sad,
就是当我们生气或是伤心的时候， 如果我们吃下巧克力或雪糕，
we feel better.
我们的感觉就会好一点。
Same process,
同样的过程，
just a different trigger.
只是用不一样的触发方式
Instead of this hunger signal coming from our stomach,
來代替原本我们胃里的饥饿讯息，
this emotional signal -- feeling sad --
这种情感上的讯息--感到伤心--
triggers that urge to eat.
触发了想吃的冲动。
Maybe in our teenage years,
也許在我們年輕的時候， 曾经也是个书呆子，
and we see those rebel kids outside smoking and we think,
我们看到这些叛逆的小子 在外面抽烟，我们就在想，
"Hey, I want to be cool."
" 嘿！我也想要耍酷 "
So we start smoking.
于是我们开始抽烟。
The Marlboro Man wasn't a dork, and that was no accident.
所以万宝路的男人看起来不呆， 这并不意外。
See cool,
看到别人耍酷，
smoke to be cool,
抽烟耍酷，
feel good. Repeat.
感觉良好，重覆。
Trigger, behavior, reward.
触发、行为、奖励。
And each time we do this,
每一次我们这样做，
we learn to repeat the process
我们学会了去重覆这个过程，
and it becomes a habit.
並养成了习惯。
So later,
所以之後，
feeling stressed out triggers that urge to smoke a cigarette
感觉有压力的时候， 就会触发欲望去抽烟
or to eat something sweet.
或是去吃一些甜的东西。
Now, with these same brain processes,
这些相同的大脑过程，
we've gone from learning to survive
让我们经历了从学习到生存，
to literally killing ourselves with these habits.
到简直是用这些习惯 在残害着我们自己的过程。
Obesity and smoking
肥胖和抽烟
are among the leading preventable causes of morbidity and mortality in the world.
是全世界数一数二會引發 病殘及死亡的可预防疾病。
So back to my breath.
所以，回到我的呼吸。
What if instead of fighting our brains,
假设我们不要再跟脑袋去抗争，
or trying to force ourselves to pay attention,
也不要再强逼自己去专注，
we instead tapped into this natural, reward-based learning process ...
而是借助这个天然的、 以奖励为本的学习过程......
but added a twist?
然后稍微改变扭转一下？
What if instead we just got really curious
假如我们变得很好奇，
about what was happening in our momentary experience?
想了解自己的瞬间体验 到底是怎样一回事？
I'll give you an example.
我给各位一个例子。
In my lab,
在我的实验室，
we studied whether mindfulness training could help people quit smoking.
我们研究冥想的训练 是不是可以帮助人们戒掉抽烟。
Now, just like trying to force myself to pay attention to my breath,
其实，就像尝试着强迫自己 去专注于呼吸一样，
they could try to force themselves to quit smoking.
他们也可以尝试着去强迫自己戒烟。
And the majority of them had tried this before and failed --
他们大部份人之前都尝试過了， 但都失败--
on average, six times.
平均来说，尝试过六次。
Now, with mindfulness training,
现在，用冥想的训练方法，
we dropped the bit about forcing and instead focused on being curious.
我们把强迫的那部份去掉， 取而代之的是专注于好奇。
In fact, we even told them to smoke.
事实上，我们甚至告诉他们去抽烟。
What? Yeah, we said, "Go ahead and smoke,
什么？是呀，我们说，" 去抽烟就对了，
just be really curious about what it's like when you do."
只是在抽烟的时候，真心的去好奇一下 抽烟到底是怎么回事。 "
And what did they notice?
结果他们觉察到了什么？
Well here's an example from one of our smokers.
让我们来看看其中的一位抽烟者怎么说。
She said, "Mindful smoking:
她说，「 专注地抽烟：
smells like stinky cheese
烟的味道闻起来就像发臭的奶酪，
and tastes like chemicals,
尝起来则像化学制品，
YUCK!"
超恶心！ 」
Now, she knew, cognitively that smoking was bad for her,
其实在认知上，她知道，抽烟会危害她，
that's why she joined our program.
正因如此，她参加我们的计划。
What she discovered just by being curiously aware when she smoked
她发现，在抽烟的时候， 只要好奇地去体会，
was that smoking tastes like shit.
就会察觉到烟的味道像大便。
Now, she moved from knowledge to wisdom.
现在，她从知识升华到智慧。
She moved from knowing in her head that smoking was bad for her
她从脑袋里开始了解到骨子里去，
to knowing it in her bones,
明白了抽烟对她有害，
and the spell of smoking was broken.
这时抽烟的魔咒就会被破解。
She started to become disenchanted with her behavior.
她开始对她的行为觉悟。
Now, the prefrontal cortex,
其实，前额叶皮质，
that youngest part of our brain from an evolutionary perspective,
从进化的角度来看， 那是我们大脑最年轻的部份，
it understands on an intellectual level that we shouldn't smoke.
它明白，理智上我们不应该抽烟。
And it tries its hardest to help us change our behavior,
然后它尝试尽最大的努力， 去帮助我们改变自己的行为、
to help us stop smoking,
帮助我们戒烟、
We call this cognitive control.
我们称之为「认知控制」。
We're using cognition to control our behavior.
我们用认知去控制自己的行为。
Unfortunately,
很不幸的是，
this is also the first part of our brain
当我们过度劳累时， 这也是我们脑袋里，
that goes offline when we get stressed out,
率先离线的部份，
which isn't that helpful.
所以不太能够帮得上忙。
Now, we can all relate to this in our own experience.
其实我们大家都可以找到 自己类似的经验。
We're much more likely to do things like yell at our spouse or kids
当我们压力过大或是很劳累时，
even though we know it's not going to be helpful.
虽然我们知道， 这样的吼叫并没有帮助。
We just can't help ourselves.
只是我们控制不了自己。
When the prefrontal cortex goes offline,
在前额叶皮质处于离线状态时，
we fall back into our old habits,
我们会坠落回老习惯，
which is why this disenchantment is so important.
这是为什么觉悟是这么的重要。
Seeing what we get from our habits
明白我们如何养成习惯
helps us understand them at a deeper level --
可以帮助我们从更深的层次去了解它们--
to know it in our bones
让我们从骨子里去明白，
so we don't have to force ourselves to hold back
那我们就不需要再强逼自己去憋住
or restrain ourselves from behavior.
或是去遏止自己的行为。
We're just less interested in doing it in the first place.
我们只是在一开始的时候 没兴趣去做这件事。
And this is what mindfulness is all about:
这就是冥想：
Seeing really clearly what we get when we get caught up in our behaviors,
当我们被自己的行为绊住的时候， 要看清楚我们得到的是什么，
becoming disenchanted on a visceral level
发自内心层次的觉悟，
and from this disenchanted stance, naturally letting go.
在觉悟的状态下， 自然地​​停止这种行为。
This isn't to say that, poof, magically we quit smoking.
這並不是，神奇的 " 噗 "的一声， 我们就戒烟了。
But over time, as we learn to see more and more clearly
而是日积月累，当我们学会 看得愈来愈清楚
the results of our actions,
我们行为所导致的结果，
we let go of old habits and form new ones.
我们就会摒除掉老习惯， 而养成了新的习惯。
The paradox here
吊诡的是，
is that mindfulness is just about being really interested
冥想是，打从内心的感到有兴趣，
in getting close and personal
每时每刻地去仔细体会
This willingness to turn toward our experience
将这种意愿转换成我们的体验
And this willingness to turn toward our experience
而将我们的意愿转换成体验
is supported by curiosity,
是源自好奇，
which is naturally rewarding.
那是先天性的奖励。
What does curiosity feel like?
好奇的感觉是怎样的呢？
It feels good.
感觉很好。
And what happens when we get curious?
我们感到好奇的时候会发生什么事情呢？
We start to notice that cravings are simply made up of body sensations --
我们会开始察觉到，瘾念其实单就是 从身体的感官所造成 --
oh, there's tightness, there's tension,
噢，那里很紧张，那边有压力
there's restlessness --
那边烦躁不安--
and that these body sensations come and go.
这些身体的感觉来来去去。
These are bite-size pieces of experiences
这些都是我们时时刻刻
that we can manage from moment to moment
都可以处理好的小体验，
rather than getting clobbered by this huge, scary craving
而不是被这巨大可怕的
In other words, when we get curious,
换句话说，当我们感到好奇時，
we step out of our old, fear-based, reactive habit patterns,
我们就走出旧有的、恐惧为本的、 回应式的习惯模式，
and we step into being.
我们从而踏进了当下。
We become this inner scientist
我们成为了热切地期待着下一个数据点的
Now, this might sound too simplistic to affect behavior.
这听起来，好像沒那容易 可以影响行为。
But in one study, we found that mindfulness training
但在一份研究报告里面， 我们发现冥想的训练，
was twice as good as gold standard therapy at helping people quit smoking.
在帮助人们戒烟的这事情上， 比黄金标准治疗法好 2 倍
So it actually works.
所以冥想真的有效。
And when we studied the brains of experienced meditators,
当我们研究资深冥想者的大脑时，
we found that parts of a neural network of self-referential processing
我们发现了神经网络里面 「自我指认流程」的部分
called the default mode network
被称为「预设模式的网络」
were at play.
正在产生引响。
Now, one current hypothesis is that a region of this network,
目前有一个关于这个 网络所在区域的假设，
called the posterior cingulate cortex,
称为「后扣带回皮质」，
is activated not necessarily by craving itself
会因为瘾念本身而引发不必要的启动，
but when we get caught up in it, when we get sucked in,
但当我们被它牵绊住， 当我们被吸进去的时候，
and it takes us for a ride.
它就会欺骗我们。
In contrast, when we let go --
相反来说，如果我们不去有意识地--
step out of the process
从里走出来，
just by being curiously aware of what's happening --
只是单纯的好奇 到底发生什么事情--
Now we're testing app and online-based mindfulness training programs
现在我们在测试手机应用程式和 以网路为基础的冥想训练课程，
that target these core mechanisms
目标就是这些核心机制，
and, ironically, use the same technology that's driving us to distraction
而讽刺的是，竟是使用 同一种也会让我们分心的科技
to help us step out of our unhealthy habit patterns
来帮助我们脱离自己不健康的习惯模式，
of smoking, of stress eating and other addictive behaviors.
像是吸烟、因压力而狂吃 和其他上瘾的行为。
Now, remember that bit about context-dependent memory?
现在，还记得刚才提过的情境记忆吗？
We can deliver these tools to peoples' fingertips
我们可以把这些最重要的
in the contexts that matter most.
内容工具传递到人们的指尖。
So we can help them
所以我们可以帮助他们
tap into their inherent capacity to be curiously aware
在渴望抽烟、遇压力乱吃或 任何不好的欲望浮现的时候，
right when that urge to smoke or stress eat or whatever arises.
利用他们的内心能力 去好奇地意识正确，
So if you don't smoke or stress eat,
所以如果你不抽烟、 也没有因为压力而狂吃，
maybe the next time you feel this urge to check your email when you're bored,
也許在下一次你无聊的时候 有股衝動想去检查电邮，
or you're trying to distract yourself from work,
或是你想在工作时间透一下气，
or maybe to compulsively respond to that text message when you're driving,
又或在开车时， 有不得不回覆讯息的义务，
see if you can tap into this natural capacity,
看看你是不是可以 借助这先天的能力，
just be curiously aware
就单纯的好奇
of what's happening in your body and mind in that moment.
到底那一刻，你的身体和心智 在发生什么事。
It will just be another chance
这可能提供了一个机会
to perpetuate one of our endless and exhaustive habit loops ...
让你持续保有这个永无止境 和消耗性的恶性循环......
or step out of it.
或是摆脱掉它。
Instead of see text message, compulsively text back,
看见讯息时，不要再--不得不的回覆
feel a little bit better --
反而应该是有蛮好的感觉--
notice the urge,
察觉到冲动，
get curious,
感到好奇，
feel the joy of letting go
感受一下不去做它的快感，
and repeat.
然后重覆。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）